ALISA BAJRAMOVIC

alisabaj@gmail.com • 847.254.0485
Seattle, WA 98122
alisabajramovic.com • LinkedIn • Github • Blog

Technical Writer & Software Engineer

I am a technical writer and software engineer who loves communicating complicated problems in clear, concise ways. My background in academic research and long-form writing taught me how to sift through large amounts of information and ask the right questions. My experience as a software engineer has given me a vast technical vocabulary and knowledge base. My work as a technical writer for a data platform has trained me to write for and speak with people from a variety of roles and perspectives in order to ensure everyone's needs are met.

Experience

Technical Writer, Affirma Consulting at Microsoft | 08/2020 – present

- Writing internal reference documents for developers at Microsoft about the Substrate data platform
- Conducting in-depth research of technical concepts and writing in ways that are clear, concise, and helpful for the end user
- Revising and updating legacy documentation to reflect software changes and in response to partner feedback
- Working closely with the project manager, software developers, and other writers to plan and execute large, long-term projects
- Interviewing engineers and project managers about their experience with the platform, and turning those interviews into specific ways to improve our team

Software Engineer, *Endocrine and Diabetes Associates* | 10/2019 – *present*

- Updating and designing website for a medical practice, working closely with physician's needs and preferences
- Built site using GoDaddy website builder, generating a 93% InSight score compared to similar online businesses

Full Stack Software Engineer, Legit Clinic | 03/2020 – 07/2020

- Independently built a new site using React and Ruby Rails that enables users to check the legitimacy of medical clinics
- Worked with a remote team, including a UX/UI designer and a project manager, to create a site with great UX/UI and flow
- Technologies: JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Airtable, Git

Front End Software Engineer, RAVO | 06/2020 – 07/2020

- Built a page of a new startup site using React, focusing on creating concise components and well-designed features
- Worked with a team of other engineers to create a ranking and voting site with social elements
- Technologies: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Postgres, Docker, Arcanist, Phabricator

Technical Skills

Markdown, Git, JavaScript, React.js, React Native, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Web Accessibility Standards (W3C WAI), HTML, CSS, Semantic UI, Heroku, Airtable, Postgres, SQLite, SQL, Docker, Phabricator, Arcanist

Technical Projects

Southern Abortion Access - Github Front End | Github Back End | Visit Deployed Site | Demo

A Ruby on Rails/React program to help people seeking abortions learn their state's laws, find local clinics, and track funding sources

- Used RestClient to save data from the Abortion Policy API to Postgres database, and Nokogiri to scrape external site
- Implemented React-Router-DOM to create a client-based router
- Used Semantic UI and CSS to enhance user experience with the program

Education

Flatiron School | Seattle, WA | 10/2019 – 01/2020

- Software Engineering Program full stack web development (Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React)
- Created five significant projects and had substantial pair programming experience

University of Glasgow | Glasgow, Scotland, UK | 09/2018 – 09/2019

- Master of Science in Gender History Graduated with Distinction (highest honors)
- Dissertation: "Family Planning in Glasgow: The Medical and Political Management of Fertility, 1950-1990"

Amherst College | Amherst, MA | 09/2014 – 05/2018

- Bachelor of Arts in History and Sexuality, Women's and Gender Studies Graduated Magna Cum Laude (GPA: 3.87/4.00)
- History Thesis: "'War Broke Their Reason': Conceptions of Shell Shock in British Society, 1918-1924"